eventespresso.com 2019-05-30

# Privacy Policy - WordPress Event Registration Ticketing Plugin - Event Espresso

**Live outside of the United States?** Please refer to our [Privacy Notice](https://eventespresso.com/privacy-notice/) for more information about how we protect your personal data.

_Your privacy is critically important to us. At Event Espresso we have a few fundamental principles:_

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our products/services.

Below is our privacy policy, which incorporates these goals.

If you have questions about this policy or your personal data please contact us.

Event Espresso LLC. (“ **Event Espresso** ”) operates several websites including EventEspresso.com, EventB.us, and EventSmart.com. It is Event Espresso’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites and providing service to our products.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Event Espresso collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Event Espresso’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Event Espresso’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Event Espresso may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Event Espresso also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on Event Espresso websites. Event Espresso only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog(s) where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Event Espresso’s websites choose to interact with Event Espresso in ways that require Event Espresso to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Event Espresso gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up to use our products to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Event Espresso are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Event Espresso collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Event Espresso. Event Espresso does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Event Espresso may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites and users of its products. Event Espresso may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Event Espresso does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

Aggregated statistics are gathered in an effort to improve our products to help you be more successful. See our User eXperience Improvement Program (UXIP) for more details.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Event Espresso discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Event Espresso’s behalf or to provide services available at Event Espresso’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Event Espresso’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Event Espresso will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Event Espresso discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Event Espresso believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Event Espresso, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Event Espresso website and have supplied your email address, Event Espresso may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Event Espresso and our products. We primarily use our website(s) and email(s) to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Event Espresso takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Event Espresso uses cookies to help Event Espresso identify and track visitors, their usage of Event Espresso website, and their website access preferences. Event Espresso visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Event Espresso’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Event Espresso’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**

If Event Espresso, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Event Espresso goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Event Espresso may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Event Espresso and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Event Espresso may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Event Espresso’s sole discretion. Event Espresso encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy.

**Privacy Notice**

If you live outside of the United States or just want to learn more about how we protect your data, then please refer to our [Privacy Notice](https://eventespresso.com/privacy-notice/).
